PREVIOUSLY…
‪（前情提要）
Are you all right, Your Royal Highness?
‪您没事吧？邸下
Royal Tutor Jung Ji-un of the Crown Prince
‪世子的书筵官 司书郑至韵
is in fact Samgaebang's real physician?
‪其实是三开房真正的医员？
-No. -Your Royal Highness!
‪-不行 ‪-邸下！
Why do you have this book?
‪这本书怎么会在这里？
The Minister of Personnel lodged an appeal for your resignation.
‪吏判大监提出了罢免你的上疏
For my resignation? I'm in need of your help.
‪罢免？
You are the only person who can help me now.
‪邸下是现在唯一能帮助我的人
There is nothing I can do for you.
‪此事我无能为力
So I advise you to stop asking.
‪因此你就死了这条心吧
You could have punished just me from the beginning.
‪当初你只要惩罚我就行了
Why are you torturing my innocent friends and putting everyone in danger?
‪为何要抓那些无辜的孩子 ‪让所有人痛苦呢？
Moreover, he deceived me and the Crown Prince.
‪欺瞒寡人与世子
The degree of his crime is quite severe.
‪其罪不轻
Who is going to get killed?
‪被杀害？你究竟是指谁？
I order you as the Crown Prince. Hand over the prisoners.
‪我以世子的身份下令 ‪将那两个孩子交出来
If you do, no one will shed a drop of blood here tonight.
‪那么今晚这里就不会流淌任何一滴血
Allow me…
‪这个问题…
to answer that question.
‪由我来回答你
I was the one…
‪移转罪犯的人
who moved the prisoners.
‪就是我
I was taught that prisons are where prisoners receive punishment,
‪殿下曾说监狱本为惩治罪人的地方
not where they are meant to die.
‪而非为处死罪人的地方
Despite that objective of His Majesty's,
‪然事实却与殿下旨意相违
their living conditions have become horrendous
‪狱中环境十分残酷
and have led to prisoners starving or freezing to death.
‪饿死或冻死的罪人不计其数
It is why I seek forgiveness regarding the unsanctioned transfer
‪因此才会未获允许就急忙移转罪犯
of said prisoners.
‪还请您原谅儿臣
You dare interrupt today's ruling
‪你就为了告诉我此事
to notify me of this frivolous matter?
‪才擅自闯入朝启中的正殿吗？
Your Majesty, I have urgent information
‪儿臣针对三开房事件
regarding the incidents at Samgaebang.
‪有急事向殿下禀告
This is not a matter His Royal Highness should involve himself in.
‪世子不该插手这件事
I'll allow it.
‪那好
Speak.
‪你说说看
Royal Tutor Jung never disobeyed the custom of our class system.
‪郑司书从未违反阶级制度
Those who actually did…
‪真正违背法理的
are them.
‪是那些人
Enter.
‪把人带进来
One is a herb gatherer
‪其中一位是直到不久前
who supplied pharmacies within the capital
‪都还在为都城药房供给药草的药草商
and one is the custodian of Literary Licentiate Choi's storage.
‪另一位是替那位崔进士家 ‪看守仓库之人
Repeat to His Majesty what you told me.
‪将你们告诉我的向殿下重述一次
The accusation that the physician of Samgaebang
‪三开房的医员
only prescribed pricey medicine is a false one.
‪专挑昂贵药材开立处方一事 ‪与事实不符
Literary Licentiate Choi over here bought all the medicinal herbs
‪是目前也在场的进士大人
available from villages
‪将整村的药材全数买下
and stocked them in the storage he owns.
‪囤积于仓库
Regardless of age, people started dying left and right
‪导致不分老少 大多数的人
due to a lack of medicine.
‪未能服用一帖药就病死
After learning the truth, Physician Jung found herbs that provide similar remedies
‪得知真相的医员 ‪找来具有类似效果的药材
and made them affordable.
‪便宜地卖给大家
It resulted in the price drop of the herbs in storage
‪这导致仓库里的药材价格暴跌
which prompted this accusation.
‪进而引起争端
Is this all true?
‪那些话都是事实吗？
Of course not, Chief State Councilor! I'm being falsely accused.
‪不是的 领相大监 这是诬陷啊
No, we speak the truth!
‪不 我们说的是事实
I have a ledger that lists all transactions of the herbs.
‪我手上有管理药材的账簿
MEDICINAL HERB INVENTORY LEDGER
‪（药材管理账簿）
Unlike the rumors surrounding Samgaebang,
‪三开房并非如传闻所言
you are saying it was a place that helped the unfortunate.
‪那里其实是帮助有困难之人的地方 ‪是这个意思吗？
It never indulged in foul play either.
‪而且他们并未做出违背情理之事？
Yes, but I guess
‪是的 不过…
that depends on what you view as following the rules and being dutiful.
‪根据你所认为的情理与道理为何
All I want to say is that it's a place that didn't go against the justice
‪我想表达的是 至少三开房并无违背
I wish to promote in this nation.
‪我未来想在这个国家看到的正义
And Royal Tutor Jung shares the very same values.
‪而郑司书也拥有同样的目标
I also believe His Royal Highness' claims to be true, Your Majesty.
‪微臣也认为邸下所言甚是 殿下
But you were the one
‪但正是你
who first raised questions regarding this matter!
‪最先对此事提出质疑的啊
Please forgive me for acting rashly
‪微臣仅依表面情况判断 ‪未经深思熟虑
without taking a deeper look into the underlying truth, Your Majesty.
‪恳请殿下原谅微臣的轻率
I hear you. However, that was not the only issue.
‪好 但那不是重点
Jung Ji-un became a royal tutor
‪郑至韵未据实以告
without disclosing his prior operations.
‪就成为侍讲院的司书
If I dare say so, Royal Tutor Jung never lied about his past endeavors.
‪恕儿臣直言 ‪郑司书从未隐瞒自己的身份
I accepted his teaching while aware of his past,
‪儿臣当初在上书筵前就已知道实情
and I'm sure you remember that I informed you of this matter.
‪也记得已经告诉过您了
But you chose not to listen to me.
‪但是殿下并未将儿臣的话听进去
In the end,
‪最后
you were the one who moved forward with appointing him as my tutor.
‪是殿下强行任命郑司书
So if anyone's to blame,
‪若要追究
it would be Your Majesty and the high officials of the court
‪难道不是未能彻查书筵官背景的殿下
who did not properly conduct a background check.
‪以及在场大臣们的错吗？
So us being negligent is to blame?
‪所以这都是寡人 ‪和大臣们的疏失引起的？
Do not forget.
‪别忘了
The path I choose
‪我所选择的路
will be your path.
‪即是您要走的路
And if you deviate from that path,
‪若偏离了那条道路
I will not forgive you,
‪无论我有多疼爱您
no matter how much I adore you.
‪我都不会原谅您
I wish to take
‪您想走的那条路
that path with you.
‪我打算与您一同走下去
Aren't you curious
‪您难道不好奇
as to in what way…
‪我要用什么方法
I wish to follow your lead?
‪来跟随您吗？
Is the Crown Prince ready to fight his battle?
‪这是世子邸下的 ‪第一份《出师表》吗？
EPISODE 7
‪第 7 集
Thank you so much.
‪真的很谢谢你
Your gratitude should be extended to His Royal Highness, not me.
‪你该道谢的对象不是我 ‪而是邸下才对
Your Royal Highness,
‪邸下
no words can possibly convey my gratitude.
‪真不知道该如何向您道谢
There is no need to thank me.
‪不需要向我道谢
I just could not sit idly by
‪我既然得知了真相
when I knew the truth.
‪就无法装作不知情
If you head to Seorin-bang,
‪你去瑞麟坊看看吧
you'll be able to reunite with your assistants.
‪你会见到你在等待的孩子们
I had no idea you'd take action in solving this issue.
‪没想到邸下会出面解决
Well…
‪因为
He's your friend, isn't he?
‪他是王兄的朋友
And he's also…
‪也是…
my tutor.
‪我的老师
JEONOKSEO
‪（典狱署）
-Ji-un. -Ji-un!
‪-大哥！ ‪-哥
Ji-un.
‪大哥
You obtained the Crown Prince's trust in a short amount of time.
‪看来你在短时间内 ‪就获得世子邸下的信任了
I'd expect no less from someone as prodigious as you.
‪也是 毕竟你从小就聪明过人
If you ever harm them again--
‪你要是敢再动他们 到时候…
I won't force you…
‪你若无意当官
to find a place within the royal court.
‪我也不会强求
But don't you dare think about being a hack of a physician again.
‪但是你休想再当医员
For your sake and your mother's especially.
‪这也是为了你和你娘着想
Just remember that it isn't easy to cope with your one and only son
‪要忍受唯一的儿子遭人议论
being chewed out.
‪并不是一件容易的事
My lady!
‪夫人！
My lady, the night is deep.
‪夫人 时间很晚了
-My lady, where are you headed? -Stop this. I can't take it anymore.
‪-夫人 这么晚了您要去哪里？ ‪-我忍无可忍了
-My lady, it's dangerous. -Let go!
‪-夫人 太危险了 ‪-放开我！
-My lady. -I won't let this slide.
‪-夫人 ‪-我这次不会坐视不管
-But it's dangerous. -What could be so dangerous?
‪-太危险了 ‪-哪里危险了？
-Let go of me! -My lady!
‪-放手！ ‪-夫人
Let go.
‪我真的…
-Those blabbermouths-- -I knew it.
‪-那些混账… ‪-我就知道会这样
I was wondering whose voice was so loud.
‪我还在想是谁嗓门这么大
Ji-un!
‪至韵
Gosh. Are you all right? Are you?
‪唉唷 你还好吗？没事吧？
Of course I am.
‪我当然没事
My lady, your shoes don't match.
‪夫人 您鞋子穿错了
You can give me those and go about your business.
‪鞋子给我 你去忙吧
Did the ladies in Bukchon speak ill of me again?
‪北村的夫人们又说我坏话了吗？
No, that's not it.
‪不是啦
They once loved to pass around the medicine you prescribed,
‪大家之前称赞你给的药还四处分享
but now they're saying ridiculous things.
‪现在却在那里火上加油
They're obviously jealous that you became a royal tutor,
‪他们一定是嫉妒你当上书筵官
so how can I let them carry on?
‪这口气我怎么忍得下来？
That's feisty coming from the inspector's better half.
‪执义夫人怎么能这么粗鲁？
From what I hear, you used to be the most timid maiden in the village.
‪听说你嫁人之前 ‪是村子里最腼腆又端庄的
My one and only son made me a salty woman, that's why.
‪还不是因为儿子让我操碎了心
Until when will you find shelter elsewhere from home?
‪你到底要在外头待到什么时候？
It's time you moved back in.
‪现在也该回家了
Your father is gravely worried about you.
‪你爹十分担心你
I'm sorry.
‪对不起
Goodness, I repeated the same thing again.
‪唉唷 我又说了同样的话 对吧？
Just come by whenever you want to. Like today.
‪你想来的时候再来吧 就像今天一样
Your room is still as it was.
‪你的房间永远都在
Success doesn't mean finding work at the palace.
‪对啊 又不是一定要入宫 ‪才算出人头地
Doing what you love and being happy is the definition of a successful life.
‪做你想做的事 过得幸福 ‪那就算出人头地了 不是吗？
So don't let others intimidate you
‪所以你在外面别气馁
and live your life as you wish.
‪跟随自己内心的感觉走
Don't let others dictate your life. Do you hear me?
‪不要顾忌别人脸色 知道吗？
What…
‪嗯？
Weren't you going to leave the palace
‪你不是救出在三开房工作的孩子
once you saved your assistants?
‪就打算离开宫里吗？
to clear my name?
‪我怎么能那么做呢？
I decided to stay where my heart lies for a while longer.
‪我决定在我心之所向之处 ‪多停留一阵子
Your heart?
‪心？
I seem to have had the wrong idea about you.
‪我先前对邸下有一点小误会
I let your nicknames Five Step Prince and Ice Prince
‪您被称为五步邸下、东冰库
cloud my judgment
‪我受那些流言影响
and assumed that you were audacious and cold-hearted.
‪误以为邸下目中无人又生性冷酷
However, that wasn't the case.
‪然而事实并非如此
Your generosity knows no limit, Your Royal Highness.
‪邸下为人心胸宽大有如泰山
You could have easily been written about in this Confucian classic.
‪您是只有在经书里才会出现的那种人
A cold-hearted soul
‪即使有人在眼前死去
who doesn't bat an eye even at the sight of death?
‪也丝毫不为所动的冷酷之人？
No, that was only a preposterous rumor.
‪不对 那全都是无稽之谈
I'm living proof of it, don't you agree?
‪我就是活生生的证人啊
That being said,
‪那么
why was His Royal Highness given the nickname Ice Prince?
‪请问东冰库邸下 ‪为何被称为东冰库呢？
Because his heart is icy cold all year round--
‪因为他一年四季都像冰块一样冷…
Ice is clear and sparkles under the sun.
‪冰块晶莹剔透
It is more elegant than any other jewel.
‪比任何宝石都来得高雅
And that is the origin
‪因而得名…
behind his nickname the Ice Prince!
‪东冰库！
Why does it feel like there's a chance of him getting a promotion before me?
‪再这样下去 ‪那小子该不会比我早升官吧？
Your Royal Highness.
‪邸下
We have fine weather today.
‪天气真好
Isn't it nice to enjoy a lecture outside for a change?
‪好久没在户外进行书筵 ‪邸下不觉得很棒吗？
You should watch where you're going.
‪请你走路看前面
Walking backward will surely make you trip and fall into a pond.
‪走路不专心小心掉进池塘里
I'm more sturdy and nimble than people think
‪别看我这样子 ‪我不仅强壮 身手又矫捷
which is why I have never tripped before--
‪这辈子从来没有摔倒…
Goodness!
‪唉唷！
Your Royal Highness.
‪邸下
How cool.
‪好帅
Wait for me, Your Royal Highness!
‪等等我啊 邸下！
THE WATER IS COLD AND THE NIGHT IS CHILLY
‪（悬崖撒手丈夫儿 水寒夜…）
WITH WIND…
‪（随…）
What have you been taking your time writing?
‪你这么认真在写什么？
WELCOME RAIN ON A SPRING NIGHT
‪（当春乃发生）
A GOOD RAIN KNOWS ITS SEASONS RIGHT
‪（好雨知时节）
"A good rain knows its seasons right."
‪“好雨知时节”
I don't think I properly expressed my gratitude
‪上次邸下出手相助
for the help I received.
‪我似乎还没正式向您道谢
Like the good rain that falls when most needed,
‪就如同一场及时雨
I will be someone who you can count on.
‪我也会在邸下有难时及时出手相救
Just like you were to me when I needed you the most.
‪就像邸下对我那般
Goodness.
‪天啊
It's raining, Your Royal Highness.
‪下雨了 邸下
Perfect timing, don't you think?
‪时机很巧吧？
A GOOD RAIN KNOWS ITS SEASONS RIGHT
‪（好雨知时节 当春乃发生）
Your Royal Highness, it's Bok-dong.
‪邸下 小的是福童
What is this about?
‪有什么事？
I see.
‪这样啊
-By the way, Bok-dong. -Yes, Your Royal Highness.
‪那个 福童
It's about Royal Tutor Jung.
‪那个郑司书
Has he been getting along with those at the royal institute?
‪他和侍讲院的人相处得融洽吗？
You have no idea. Life at the palace must be like second nature to him now
‪别提了 他的宫中生活如鱼得水
considering how he brings them alcohol and gladly trades shifts.
‪他会带酒给他们 还很乐意换班
He is as amiable as they get and is highly praised by the rest.
‪非常和蔼可亲 大家都对他赞誉有加
You can tell
‪从他对您的态度来看
that he's nothing like his father from the way he acts toward you.
‪不觉得他跟他爹完全是不同人吗？
Why do you ask about him though?
‪但您为何要问这个呢？
What? No reason.
‪嗯？
If you're done, dismiss yourself already.
‪若你整理完了就退下
Yes, Your Royal Highness. I wish you a good night.
‪是 邸下 那您休息吧
A GOOD RAIN KNOWS ITS SEASONS RIGHT
‪（好雨知时节 当春乃发生）
Since His Majesty is in poor health,
‪由于主上龙体欠安
it might not be a bad idea for the Crown Prince
‪让世子负责接待
to greet the envoys.
‪并无坏处
I'm well aware of your desire to give more authority
‪左相渐渐地想将重责大任交付给世子
to His Royal Highness.
‪我也不是不清楚
Then I'll trust that
‪那么微臣就相信
you will make a formal request to His Majesty.
‪娘娘会向殿下上奏请示了
But I hope you don't think that I will blindly act
‪不过你该不会认为你的意思
according to your desires.
‪我一定会听从吧？
It's what I noticed with the incident involving the royal tutor,
‪前几天书筵官的事情也是
but lately,
‪左相近来
I haven't been pleased about you
‪所做的越权之举
overstepping your authority.
‪实在令我很在意
Overstepping my authority?
‪越权？
I…
‪微臣
vowed my allegiance to the former king
‪可是和先王歃血为盟的
with blood on my lips.
‪功臣
How could you possibly say such a thing
‪我卖命帮助他登上王位
when I put my life on the line to help him take the throne?
‪您怎么能说如此令人伤心的话呢？
I understand your fondness for the Crown Prince,
‪我明白你疼惜世子的心
but His Majesty is also someone you must serve.
‪但主上也是左相该辅佐之人
If you offend him in any way, you will answer to me.
‪这等情事我是不会容忍的
Your Highness, then wouldn't it only be fair that you lead by example?
‪那么娘娘要率先做好榜样啊
What?
‪你说什么？
More and more key officials are being appointed in your favor.
‪由大妃殿安排担任要职的人日益增加
You should never forget
‪娘娘欲培养娘家势力
that it is I who have been considerate of your desire
‪能理解您这种心情的没有别人 ‪只有我一个
to give your family power.
‪您可不能忘了
Of course not, Your Highness.
‪这怎么可能呢？
All I want
‪微臣所希望的只是
to no longer be a threat.
‪不再猖獗狂妄！
That is all.
‪仅此而已
Therefore…
‪因此…
I suggest we refrain from pointless squabbles, Your Highness.
‪我们别再进行无谓的口舌之争了
A foot disorder?
‪足疾？
-Has Father's foot disease returned? -Yes.
‪父王的足疾复发了吗？
His Majesty has been overwhelmed with state affairs
‪殿下日理万机
and his prognosis isn't good.
‪而且他的预后不佳
Aside from Court Lady Kim and Eunuch Hong,
‪话说回来
he's the first to protect you from close proximity.
‪这是头一次有人守在邸下身边
Hasn't it been uncomfortable?
‪您不会感到不自在吗？
I should learn to get used to it.
‪我得习惯啊
I cannot forever be served by only Court Lady Kim and Eunuch Hong.
‪身边总不能永远 ‪只有金尚宫和洪内官吧
Right.
‪是
Your Majesty.
‪殿下
Leave the herbal tonic.
‪汤药放着就可以走了
Father.
‪父王
It is I.
‪是孩儿
I see. What brings you by?
‪你来这有什么事？
I would like to make a request.
‪我有事前来请求父王
Please let me be in charge of receiving the envoys.
‪这次接待使臣团一事 ‪请交给孩儿负责
Aren't you aware of that being Prince Jaeun's responsibility?
‪你难道不知道接待使臣团 ‪是由者隐君负责的吗？
Actually, I was hoping
‪使臣团进宫时
to greet them in your place when they arrive at the palace.
‪我想代替父王负责接待他们
I'm aware that the same request came from the Queen Dowager as well.
‪听说大妃殿也已奏请了
And who says that is what I want?
‪究竟是谁说了算？
I will greet the envoys according to custom.
‪这次使臣团依照惯例由寡人来接待
You are dismissed.
‪你退下吧
Father,
‪父王
do you still not have faith in me?
‪您至今还是不相信孩儿吗？
I am well aware that you were against my installation as Crown Prince.
‪我知道父王反对册封我为世子
Was it…
‪单纯是…
because of my maternal grandfather?
‪因为我外祖父而已吗？
Or…
‪还是…
was it…
‪因为谦…
because of Gyeom?
‪那孩子的关系？
What is your reason…
‪事到如今
for bringing that up after all this time?
‪你提起那件事做什么？
I understand that you find my grandfather to be difficult.
‪我知道父王觉得我的外祖父很难相处
But this is what I want for myself.
‪但这完全出自我个人的意愿
I ask you
‪这次请您务必
to put your faith in me this time.
‪相信孩儿
I…
‪孩儿
won't let you down.
‪不会让您失望的
He sure is adorable.
‪他真可爱
There is something quite adorable about him.
‪他有很可爱的一面
How are preparations coming along at the guesthouses for the envoys?
‪太平馆和慕华馆准备得如何了？
Have you heard from the governor who went to Uiju to accompany the envoys?
‪以接伴使名义 ‪去宜州的观察使有任何消息吗？
You should pace yourself and take it easy.
‪慢慢来 请不要太勉强
I am taking His Majesty's place.
‪我是代替殿下去接待
There can be no room for error.
‪即使有困难也得好好表现
Let your mind rest for now. We have to be at the market soon.
‪你先稍作休息 ‪我们待会就得去一趟集市
I will first retrieve the report sent by the governor.
‪我去拿观察使送来的奏折
Your Royal Highness.
‪邸下
I hear lectures have been canceled to focus on greeting the envoys.
‪听说您因为接待的事 ‪暂时无法进行书筵了
Yes, I'm afraid I won't be able to attend for the time being.
‪是的 我短时间内无法听课了
I see.
‪这样啊
Since you're busy, I'll keep it short.
‪您看起来很忙 臣简单说明一下就走
Not even the legendary physician Hua Tuo has seen these pills
‪这个是连传说中的名医华佗 ‪都从未见过的药丸
which were made with a drop of dragon tears--
‪内含一滴龙眼泪…
Do you have nothing to do? Why don't I ask Royal Scholar Yang to--
‪你闲来无事可做吗？去转告辅德…
Hardly. I actually have urgent business to address.
‪不 臣还有事情要忙
Take some when you are having a difficult time.
‪您留着等到极度疲惫时再服用
It will give you courage and relieve you of anxiety.
‪它会让您产生勇气并消除您的不安
Then…
‪那臣先告辞了
Oh, right.
‪对了
Was it Royal Tutor Jung who just came by?
‪刚才走出去的人是郑司书吗？
No one can match his anti-climactic ways.
‪没人比他更无聊了
They are all of good quality.
‪品质都很好啦
As if.
‪最好是
Let me take a look since I know a thing or two.
‪让我看看 我很有眼光的
I'll take this one.
‪好 就这个吧
Have them delivered to Samgaebang.
‪把东西送到三开房
This one right here.
‪这边这个
And this as well as this.
‪还有这个 这个也要
-You know what? Just send them all. -Yes, my lady.
‪别这么麻烦了 ‪将这里的东西全都送过去
They are all to be sent to Samgaebang?
‪这些都要送到三开房吗？
Like I said, I owe them that much.
‪我说过我欠他们一点人情啊
What on earth?
‪怎么回事？
You must be the type to apologize with gifts rather than words.
‪比起用口头表达 ‪你好像更喜欢用金钱来表示歉意
Oh, well…
‪那是因为…
Wait, is that wrong?
‪怎么？有人规定不行吗？
I'm apologizing for my wrongdoing by buying them what they need the most.
‪我赠予对方最需要的东西来还人情
I only do so because I can afford it.
‪而我也有那个能力 所以才这么做
I'm just saying.
‪我只是说说
Anyway, why are you carrying around that hand plow?
‪不过你为何拿着锄头到处走？
Oh, this? I'm looking for some flowers to plant.
‪这个啊？我想拿点花来种
I can't afford to buy them like someone I know,
‪我不像某人一样有能力
so I must acquire them myself.
‪我必须靠自己
Wait.
‪那个…
Forgive me.
‪我很抱歉
For putting you in a predicament, I mean.
‪我是指害你为难的事
I wanted to apologize in person,
‪我原本想亲自向你道歉
but I couldn't muster up the courage.
‪但一直无法鼓起勇气
Why are you laughing?
‪你在笑什么？
Well, because I was only joking.
‪没有 我只是开玩笑的
Besides, you shouldn't apologize.
‪这件事你根本不必道歉
It's not like you told lies just to get me into trouble.
‪你也不是凭空捏造事实
Never did I think
‪没想到你是这种人
you'd be a fun person to tease.
‪捉弄你还蛮有意思的
Let's see.
‪我看看
Why do you wish to plant flowers within the palace grounds though?
‪不过你为何要在宫里种花？
Well, they're pretty. That's why.
‪因为很漂亮嘛
We should hang up more square lanterns to light up the streets more.
‪我们应该多挂一些方灯笼 ‪让街道更加明亮
-Will do, Your Royal Highness. -Good.
‪-我会的 ‪-嗯
And the decorations?
‪彩棚要怎么办？
They should also be prepared accordingly.
‪彩棚也理当准备好
What's the matter?
‪你怎么了？
It's nothing.
‪没事
Do you know them?
‪这两位是？
I mean, they are colleagues I work with.
‪他们是和我一起共事的人
Well, I guess.
‪这个嘛 没错
I see.
‪这样啊
May I ask who we're speaking to?
‪那请问这位是？
I am Shin So-eun.
‪我叫辛素恩
There are no other empty seats,
‪似乎没位子了
-so go ahead-- -Actually, since we ran into each other,
‪-那就让给两位… ‪-等等
why don't we sit down for a meal?
‪就一起用餐吧
Four bowls of soup with rice, please.
‪这里要四碗汤饭
Didn't you say you were busy?
‪你还说你很忙
Never did I imagine you having an affectionate side, Royal Tutor Jung.
‪我都不知道郑司书有如此温柔的一面
Affectionate?
‪温柔？
How pretty.
‪很美呢
The flowers, I mean.
‪那些花
Oh, these.
‪这些啊？
He spared me a few.
‪这是公子分送给我的
Anyway, how do you two know each other?
‪话说你们两位是怎么认识的？
Well, that's…
‪那个 就是…
It's a very long story.
‪唉唷 这说来话长
Here's the food you ordered.
‪汤饭来了
Goodness. We should eat first.
‪唉唷 我们还是先吃饭吧
-Please enjoy. -Thank you.
‪-请慢用 ‪-谢谢
All right. Allow me to add a spoonful.
‪来 我帮你们各加一匙
-Allow me. -It's fine. I'll do it myself.
‪-我来吧 ‪-不用了 我自己来
This is more of my specialty, so let me do it.
‪这是我的专长 给我吧
I said it's fine!
‪我说不用了！
Goodness. Are you all right?
‪天啊 没事吧？
I'll do it myself.
‪我自己来
Lord Jung, your sleeves are also stained.
‪公子 你的衣服上也有好多
I'm… I'm fine, but…
‪我…我没事啦
GWANGHWAMUN
‪（光化门）
I guess it's been a while since you set foot
‪公公 您这是阔别多年
in your homeland.
‪重新踏上故土了
Homeland? What a joke.
‪什么故土？
NOKUNGAK
‪（绿云阁）
We did our best to make your stay here with us
‪我们已尽量安排您的日常起居
as comfortable as possible.
‪以使得住得舒心
I do hope everything is up to par.
‪还有招待不周的地方 请你见谅
We appreciate all you have done for us.
‪谢谢你的安排
You can speak more at ease now for we have prepared much as well.
‪你们以后说话可以轻松点
This ornamental knife has accompanied us from Ming.
‪这把妆刀一路从明国 ‪跟着我们来到这里
It's a lucky one, don't you think?
‪真是好命
I'd rather rest, so please leave us.
‪我累了 请你们都出去
I'm sure you're aware that a new emperor ascended to the throne a year ago.
‪你知道一年前新皇帝即位的事吧？
From what I hear, those two played a major role.
‪他们两个就是当时 ‪皇帝即位的关键角色
This way, please.
‪这边请
They await you.
‪直接进去就行了
I'm glad you're here.
‪快过来
Why is Lord Sangheon meeting with Royal Tutor Jung?
‪尚宪君为何要见郑司书？
Royal Tutor Jung has a history with the Vice Minister of Rites,
‪据说郑司书和礼部侍郎交情很好
so he must be here to greet him.
‪可能是要去打声招呼
Would you like to join them?
‪邸下要过去看看吗？
And say what at an uninvited event?
‪我这个不速之客过去做什么呢？
I'd only be interrupting them.
‪只会打扰到他们
I heard I was urgently summoned.
‪急着找我的人
Was it by you?
‪就是爹吗？
I'm afraid I came to the wrong place.
‪我似乎走错地方了
I'm the one who had you summoned.
‪是我找你过来的
Physician Jung!
‪郑医员！
It's been too long.
‪好久不见
What brings you here?
‪你怎么会在这里？
I couldn't locate you in Ming, so I thought the Left State Councilor
‪我在明国都找不到的救命恩人 ‪左相说要让我们见面
was pulling my leg when he said he'd let me meet you.
‪我还不敢相信
Who knew we'd meet again like this?
‪谁能料到我们会像这样再相见呢？
Left State Councilor, I'm truly grateful.
‪真的非常感谢你 左相大监
To find out that one of my people saved your life
‪我的人正好是礼部侍郎的恩人
was a great shock on my part.
‪我才着实地吓了一跳
I guess this is what destiny looks like.
‪这就是命运和缘分吧
As if that even qualifies as saving one's life.
‪因为那点小事就把他当救命恩人
That's a little dramatic.
‪也太夸张了吧
I'm afraid I must apologize.
‪我得先失陪了
Duty calls at the Office of the Inspector General.
‪宪府有事要处理 请原谅我先离席
Physician Jung, allow me to pour you a drink.
‪郑医员 让我为你倒杯酒吧
It truly has been too long.
‪真是好久不见
I agree.
‪是啊
So the rumors about the Left State Councilor
‪人家都说朝鲜的所有钱财 ‪都在左相家的仓库里
being the richest in Joseon were true.
‪看来所言不假
Then tell me. What is it that he wants?
‪说吧 左相想要的是什么？
He was hoping to be given permission to develop the land in Yeoyeon.
‪他想得到关于闾延土地开发的许可
Yeoyeon?
‪闾延？
Barbarians constantly invade that land. Why would he want to develop…
‪他为何想要蛮族 ‪经常出没之地的开发权？
I see.
‪我知道了
He wishes to build an army under the pretense of protecting the border.
‪他想以守卫边境为由 ‪培养他自己的军队
How greedy of him.
‪野心还真大啊
Let him know that he does not need to worry.
‪那请转告他不必担心
Thank you for the warm welcome.
‪非常感谢诸位的热情款待
However, if you had focused more of your energy
‪但你们有闲工夫举办宴会
on the roads leading to Joseon,
‪倒不如多花点心思 ‪整修前来朝鲜的要道
I wouldn't be so fatigued from the trip.
‪我就不会受舟车劳顿之苦了
That means we'd be clearing a path for the barbarians up north,
‪这就等同帮北方的蛮族开辟道路
which is why we've been hesitant.
‪因此不能贸然整修道路
You still should have cleared a road to Ming though.
‪那至少要开通往明国的道路吧
Developing the land in Yeoyeon will make trading with Ming less demanding.
‪若开发闾延那边的土地 ‪明国与朝鲜之间的贸易也会更加便利
That place is a strategic point for our defense.
‪那里是军事要冲
Hasty decisions cannot be made.
‪不能贸然触碰
That's why I'm offering my assistance.
‪所以我才要帮你啊
I will mention the issues regarding Yeoyeon to the Emperor,
‪我会向皇帝禀报关于闾延一事
so all I suggest is that you send a quick response.
‪请殿下尽快给予答复
Goodness.
‪天啊
Isn't she beautiful?
‪她很不错
Especially the one in the second row.
‪我喜欢第二排的那位
Is there a girl who has caught your eye?
‪那里面有你中意的人吗？
Please do not hesitate to tell me.
‪你尽管开口
It can be ten or a hundred. I'll make sure you receive them tonight.
‪不管要多少人 ‪我都会负责送到你手中
I hear that girls sent as offerings are quite adored.
‪据闻去明国当贡女的女人非常得宠
One of them was blessed into becoming an imperial concubine.
‪其中还有人受到皇帝恩宠成为后宫
The girl to serve you tonight
‪今晚将服侍你的人
will also be a lucky one.
‪是多么幸运啊
I see.
‪那好
So I can have my pick of girls?
‪我只要开口就行了是吧？
Your request is my command.
‪这是当然的
From what I hear, your wife's beauty is blinding.
‪我听说你的夫人姿色不错
Could I take her back with me?
‪我能趁此机会把她带走吗？
Pardon?
‪什么？
Goodness. That was quite the jest.
‪唉唷 你怎么开这种玩笑？
A jest?
‪玩笑？
Then were you taunting me just now?
‪那你这是在耍我吗？
Being sent to Ming as an offering is an honor
‪你嘴上说去当贡女很好
but not when it comes to your own family?
‪却不愿自己的家人被带走是吧？
No, that is not what I meant.
‪不是的 我不是那个意思
What is the meaning of this?
‪到底怎么回事？
It's just that this man made promises to me that he can't keep.
‪是这个人对我做了无法兑现的承诺
I will punish him accordingly once I gather all the facts,
‪寡人了解事情原委后 ‪会采取适当的处置
so please let your anger subside.
‪请你息怒
If needed,
‪有需要的话
he can be executed on the spot.
‪当场处决他就行了
Wait. But…
‪等等 可是…
Please spare my life!
‪饶命啊！天啊！
That is enough.
‪够了
You are in the palace of Joseon.
‪这里是朝鲜的宫廷
His Majesty stated that he'd get to the truth,
‪殿下已承诺会确认事情原委
so let our system take over.
‪我们将依法处理
Leave and await your ruling.
‪退下等待你的处分
Yes, Your Royal Highness!
‪遵命
This isn't your place.
‪这你不应该插手
Allow me to greet you.
‪请容我向你致意
I am Jung Ji-un, a royal tutor at the royal institute.
‪我是侍讲院的司书郑至韵
You seem to be upset at this festive banquet,
‪你在开心的宴会上心情似乎不太愉悦
so I'd like to serve you a drink.
‪所以我想帮你倒杯酒
Would you accept it?
‪你愿意接受吗？
I'd consider it a great honor.
‪微臣会引以为荣
You speak out of place knowing that you are favored
‪你仗着有礼部侍郎当靠山 ‪在此放肆的样子
by the Vice Minister of Rites.
‪真是不堪入目
Get lost.
‪给我滚
Because the drink was from you,
‪也许因为这是太监给的酒
it was divine.
‪味道特别香甜
Is that so?
‪是吗？
Then have some more.
‪那就多喝一点吧
That's about enough.
‪差不多就好了
Do you not realize that you're dishonoring the Emperor
‪再继续失礼下去 ‪将有损皇帝陛下的颜面
by not showing courtesy?
‪你真的不知道吗？
Yes, that is enough.
‪别再闹了
So this is where you were, Your Royal Highness.
‪原来您在这里 邸下
Did you have to make me feel uneasy by doing what I didn't order you to do?
‪你为何要擅作主张 ‪让人如此难堪呢？
It was an important banquet.
‪这是很重要的场合啊
I was only worried that things would escalate.
‪我只是担心会发生更难堪的事
It is not your job to worry about me.
‪担心我不是你的职责
Pretend you didn't see anything
‪看了要假装没看到
or hear anything from now on.
‪听了也要装作没听到
That is how you will be.
‪请你以后都这么做
Wait. There's another child. Go and get him.
‪停 那还有一个小孩 去抓回来
-Yes, sir.
‪-是
Sit down.
‪坐下
It is not your job to worry about me.
‪担心我不是你的职责
Is this what you serve as food?
‪你们端上来的这叫食物吗？
Is there a problem?
‪有什么问题吗？
That'd be my question to you.
‪这是我要问的
What you served is nothing but waste.
‪你们所准备的食物水准全都这副模样
What is one supposed to eat?
‪究竟要人吃什么呢？
Forgive me.
‪很抱歉
I had the kitchen prepare what you enjoy,
‪我已吩咐要准备你喜欢的菜肴
but they must not suit your palate.
‪但似乎不太合你胃口
Prepare the food again.
‪重新准备菜肴
-Yes, Your Royal Highness.
‪-是 邸下
Has a decision been made regarding the man who taunted me last night?
‪昨晚在宴会上戏弄我的人怎么样了？
His mouth should have been ripped at the corners
‪应该要撕烂他的嘴
to stop him from spewing nonsense.
‪让他无法再胡说八道
The Office of the Inspector General is reviewing the case.
‪宪府正在厘清真相
He will be severely punished once they come to a ruling,
‪一旦查明罪状将会严加惩处
so please let your anger subside.
‪请你息怒
How about you just let me deal with him instead?
‪现在就将他交给我处置如何？
Executing the punishment myself means less work for you.
‪若我替你惩罚他 ‪应该能帮你省点事吧
Even a man guilty of treason is punished by law and custom.
‪即使是犯了大逆之罪的罪人 ‪也要依照法律来处理
So I suggest…
‪所以请你
you drop this.
‪别再提那件事了
Acting tough, are we?
‪真会装模作样
What…
‪你刚才…
did you just say?
‪说了什么？
What do you mean?
‪你是指什么？
What was that?
‪这是在做什么？
You dare treat me with disdain?
‪你一个下人是在无视我吗？
How dare you communicate in code in my presence!
‪竟敢当着我的面密谈？
That… That is not true, my lord.
‪不…不是那样的
Communicating in code? That is hardly true.
‪岂能说是密谈？没有这回事
I will have the food served again.
‪我会请人重新上菜
Follow me.
‪跟我过来
How dare you follow him out.
‪你要跟去哪里？
Damned wench, you just don't know your place, do you?
‪你这搞不清楚自己身份的放肆东西
Court Lady Kim!
‪尚宫娘娘！
What are you doing?
‪你这是在做什么？
As you can see, I'm teaching her some manners.
‪正如你所见 ‪我在教训不懂规矩的下人
Why? Does this require proper procedure too?
‪怎么？这种事也需要走程序吗？
Do you know what I despise the most?
‪你知道我最讨厌的是什么吗？
Words or actions of disrespect which you just showed.
‪就是像你刚才所做的瞧不起我的举动
Today, you will be taught some manners.
‪我今天就教教你规矩
Court Lady Kim!
‪天啊 尚宫娘娘！
Court Lady Kim…
‪尚宫娘娘
Oh, no.
‪天啊
Court Lady Kim…
‪金尚宫
Your Royal Highness…
‪邸下
- Your Royal Highness, you must not!
‪-万万不可啊 邸下！
You must not do this. Your Royal Highness, no!
‪不可以这么做啊 邸下！
Oh, no. Your Royal Highness…
‪天啊 邸下！
Your Royal Highness, you did the right thing.
‪邸下确实做得很好
If you are disgruntled, take it up with me.
‪若有不满就直接告诉我
Leave the innocent alone.
‪不要伤及无辜的人！
People like you are hypocrites who pretend to care for the people.
‪将故作替百姓着想的可恶之徒
And I want to destroy people like you.
‪全数踩在脚底下 就是我的期望
You saw someone suspicious in the Chief Eunuch's chambers?
‪您在太监的住所看到可疑之人？
I must look into the Chief Eunuch.
‪得着手调查太监才行
Until the day you leave Joseon,
‪在太监离开朝鲜前
security at this guesthouse will be strengthened.
‪会再加强太平馆的护卫
If you ever go after her, I will make you pay for it!
‪你要是敢动她分毫 ‪我绝不会放过你！
Thank you for helping me.
‪谢谢你与我并肩同行
I would like to continue to do so by your side.
‪臣日后也想一直陪在您身边
That is only if you will allow it, Your Royal Highness.
‪只要您同意的话